XtraMath Privacy Policy

Introduction

XtraMath is committed to protecting data privacy. We strictly adhere to this Privacy Policy, whichexplains what user data we collect and how we use it. This policy and our Terms of Service areknown collectively as our “Terms.” We may change these Terms from time to time, but willprovide notice as specified in the Terms of Service document.

This policy is effective May 25, 2018, and replaces our prior privacy policy.

Summary

● We collect the minimum amount of data required to operate ourprogram.● We use parents’ and teachers’ Personal Data to operate our program and, with theirpermission, to contact them about the program.● We use students’ Personal Data only to operate our program.● We use de-identified student data to improve our program.● We protect student data and have signed the Student Privacy Pledge.● We do not advertise to students, sell their data, or profile them in any way.● We comply with applicable data privacy laws, such as FERPA, COPPA, and GDPR.● We never sell user data to third parties.

What Data We Collect

XtraMath collects the minimum amount of data required to operate our program. Below wesummarize the data we collect on students, teachers, and parents. For an up-to-date list thatshows what user data we collect, and how we use that data, see Appendix B, Record of DataProcessing.

Definitions

● Data includes all information connected with a person’s or educational entity’s use ofXtraMath. This includes, but is not limited to, Personal Data, metadata, usage andperformance data.● Personal Data includes any data that can directly or indirectly identify an individualperson. For example: an email address is always considered Personal Data; a student’sgrade level generally is not, but could be in conjunction with other information.

1 of 9

● School includes: individual schools; teachers acting on behalf of schools; schooldistricts; and other local educational entities.

Student Data

We collect a student’s first name, grade level, and program settings from the student’s parent orteacher. As the student uses XtraMath, we collect usage and performance data, such as whenthey signed in, how many questions they answered correctly, and how long it took them toanswer questions. If a student signs in via a single sign-on provider, such as Google, we collectan identifier from the provider that allows us to authenticate their sign-in. We do not collect thestudent email address that may be used for such a sign-in.

Other personal information about the student could be inferred from data that we collect. If astudent account belongs to a class, for example, then we could infer that they attend a certainschool.

Parent Data

We collect a parent’s name and email address when they sign up for an account. If they sign upusing a single sign-on provider, we also collect an identifier that allows us to authenticate theirsign-in. We also collect some metadata and account settings, such as their time zone, thelanguage they used to sign up, and their email preferences.

A parent supplies a password when they create an account. The password is hashed(scrambled) on the user’s computer before it is ever sent to XtraMath. We do not have access toa user’s original password, and cannot obtain it from the hashed version that we receive.

Other personal information about the parent could be inferred from data that we collect. Forexample, we could infer that a parent whose account is linked to a student account is the parentor guardian of that student.

Teacher Data

We collect the same data for teacher accounts as parent accounts, with a few additions. Forexample, we collect the name by which students address the teacher, such as “Ms. Smith.” Wealso collect information about each class that the teacher creates, such as its name and its enddate.

Other personal information about the teacher could be inferred from data we collect. Forexample, we could infer that the teacher works at a specific school based on their emailaddress.

2 of 9

How We Use and Share Data

XtraMath processes user data in order to establish and maintain accounts, to provideeducational activities to students, to compile and deliver reports about those activities toteachers and parents, and to understand and improve our program’s effectiveness. For anup-to-date list that shows the specific types of user data we collect, and how we use that data,see Appendix B, Record of Data Processing.

Student Data

A student’s Personal Data is used internally to provide the student with appropriate educationalactivities, and to report their performance to their parents and teachers. We may access studentPersonal Data when providing customer support or investigating a reported issue with ourprogram.

Parent and Teacher Data

A parent’s or teacher’s Personal Data is used internally for sign-in purposes and, withpermission, to send them reports, announcements, and alerts related to XtraMath. We mayaccess a parent’s or teacher’s Personal Data when providing them with requested support.

Sharing Personal Data with Third Parties

We release Personal Data to third parties only in the following circumstances:

● When the user requests the disclosure, such as a teacher sharing their class withanother teacher.● When the third party is a trusted service provider, and the data is required to adequatelyperform the service. We carefully vet our service providers and their security practices.For details, see Appendix A, List of Third Party Providers.● When required by law or a court order.● In the event of a joint venture, sale or merger with a third party. The third party would berequired to uphold our Terms, including our Privacy Policy for all existing accounts. Wewould provide advance notice before sharing data with that third party.

XtraMath never releases Personal Data for any kind of third-party advertising.

Use of De-identified Data

We may use de-identified usage data internally to analyze and improve our educationalservices, and to develop new products or features. We will never attempt to re-identify data thathas been de-identified.

3 of 9

We may release de-identified data to educational researchers for the purpose of evaluating theeffectiveness of our program. We will not release de-identified data unless we are confident itcannot be re-identified, due to the removal of all direct and indirect personal identifiers, and theeducational researchers have agreed in writing that they will not attempt to re-identify anyindividuals, classes, or Schools.

We may use aggregate de-identified data, such as the number of users of our service, forpromotional purposes.

How We Securely Store Data

XtraMath takes security seriously. We implement a variety of industry-standard securitymeasures to prevent any unauthorized access to our users’ data. Such measures include, butare not limited to: data minimization; encrypting data in transit via HTTPS; hashing sensitivedata, like passwords; deletion of outdated data; locked physical facilities; employee training; andadministrator account security.

Data Storage and International Transfer

XtraMath stores and processes all data on servers in the United States. All servers that storeXtraMath data are operated by trusted third party processors with whom we have contractualData Processing Addendums. Our providers are certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield andSwiss-US Privacy Shield, to better protect the data of our international users. For details, seeAppendix A, List of Third Party Providers.

Data Breach Response

While we use industry-standard practices to safeguard data, no service can guarantee absolutedata security. We have a Breach Response Plan, which we will follow if we ever discover thatPersonal Data has been accessed improperly. As part of our response, we will: take action tostop further data loss or unauthorized access; investigate how the breach occurred; promptlycontact all affected users via email; and contact law enforcement and government agencieswhen appropriate.

Data Retention and Deletion

XtraMath retains Personal Data only for as long as necessary to ensure continuity of mathskill-building for students, and for the convenience of parents and teachers. We close useraccounts, and delete all associated identifiable data, upon request. Most types of data are alsodeleted automatically after a certain amount of time has passed. For details, see Appendix B,Record of Data Processing.

4 of 9

We may retain de-identified, aggregate data, which cannot identify any individual user, forresearch and program improvement purposes. Such data is deleted once no longer necessaryfor these purposes.

We will provide certification of data deletion upon request.

Compliance with Data Privacy Laws

XtraMath intends to comply with the data privacy and data protection laws of all jurisdictionswhere it operates. See the XtraMath and Student Data Privacy whitepaper for the latestinformation on compliance. Some specific examples of legislation that we comply with aredescribed below.

United States

Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA): As a non-profit organization, XtraMath isnot subject to COPPA. Nevertheless, we fully comply with the law as if we were subject to it.Children under the age of 13 may not create accounts. We only collect usage and performancedata from students as a result of their performing educational activities, and we only use thatdata for educational purposes. If we gain actual knowledge that a child is using XtraMathwithout the appropriate consent, we terminate the account.

Family Education Rights Protection Act (FERPA): Schools in the United States may providestudent data to XtraMath while complying with FERPA. When a School provides us with astudent’s Personal Data (or PII — Personally Identifiable Information) under the FERPA schoolofficial exemption, they remain in control of that data. XtraMath will only use and disclose thatdata as specified in our Terms and as allowed by law.

International

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR): XtraMath affirms and respects all data subject'srights under GDPR. We minimize the data we collect and process, and use data only asdescribed in this policy. For detailed information about what data we process, for what purpose,for how long, and our basis for doing so under the GDPR, see Appendix B, Record of DataProcessing. To object to processing, or to request data deletion or access, contact our DataProtection Officer at privacy@xtramath.org.

5 of 9

Cookies and Local Storage

XtraMath intends to discontinue the use of cookies by August 1, 2018.

XtraMath uses two types of cookies. These cookies can be cleared via browser settings —aboutcookies.org provides cookie management instructions for many specific browsers.

● Google Analytics cookies allow us to see data such as the number of site visitors weget, and which pages they visit the most.● Vimeo cookies are stored when users play the videos on our homepage, and primarilykeep track of the video player settings.

The XtraMath website uses “LocalStorage” files to remember a user’s sign-in information (if theychoose to do so). We also use “SessionStorage” to improve performance during studentactivities by temporarily storing activity data on the device. Use of LocalStorage andSessionStorage is not required to use XtraMath. Users can remove remembered sign-ininformation at any time via the appropriate sign-in page. Users can also clear all LocalStorageby using the “Clear now” button on our support page, or via browser settings.

The XtraMath mobile apps use application data for the same purposes as browser LocalStorageand SessionStorage. Users can still remove remembered sign-in information via the app’ssign-in pages. Uninstalling the app will remove all locally stored data. Some devices also allowusers to clear locally stored app data without uninstalling the app.

Contact Us

For data privacy questions or concerns, to object to processing, or to request access to ordeletion of your or your child’s Personal Data, email us at privacy@xtramath.org. You may alsowrite to us at: XtraMath, 4700 42nd Ave SW #580, Seattle, WA 98116

6 of 9

Appendix A: List of Third Party Providers

This list will be kept up-to-date to include all third-party providers with which XtraMath sharesuser data.

ProviderName

Data shared with Provider Purpose Relevant Policies

AWS User account data, includingname, email address, andprogram usage.

Database hosting via remoteservers

Privacy Policy

Google Anonymous ID created bycookie

Website analytics Privacy PolicyOpt-out Browser Add-on

MaxMind IP address Geolocation service Privacy Policy

Vimeo Anonymous ID created bycookie, video player settings

Enable playback of embeddedvideos (remember volume, ifvideo is paused, etc)

Privacy Policy

7 of 9

Appendix B: Record of Data Processing

We have compiled this record in order to provide users with as much transparency as possibleinto how we use their data. This record also helps us to comply with European law. Unlessotherwise noted in the record below, we process user data based on our legitimate interests.

AccountType

Type of Data Processing Purpose Deletion

Student

First name, PIN, parent orteacher email, class

Account access and identification Upon account closure1.Some information isdeleted upon removalfrom the class or linkedaccount.

Single-sign-on providerand hashed ID

Account access using optional3rd party credential

Upon request or accountclosure1

Grade level Determine initial activity level.When de-identified andaggregated, used to analyzeprogram usage.

Upon account closure1

Program settings: currentprogram, UI options,preferred language, etc.

Activity customization. Whende-identified and aggregated,used to analyze program usage.

Upon account closure1

Activity data Activity customization andcreation of progress reports.When de-identified andaggregated, used to analyzeprogram usage.

Upon account closure1.Some data is deletedwhen user restarts aprogram. Detailedactivity data is deletedafter one year.

Parent orTeacher

Name, “addressed as”name, email address,hashed password

Account access and identification Upon account closure2, 3

Email address Send announcements, alerts,reports, and/or reminders viaemail

Processing ceases uponrequest. Data deletionupon account closure2, 3

Email address Share with linked accounts thathave access to same student orclass (for increased transparencyand security of student data)

Data deletion uponaccount closure2, 3

Account settings: accounttype, email preferences,time zone, etc.

Create progress reports andmaintain data preferences

Upon account closure2, 3

8 of 9

Parent orTeacher

Electronic identifiers:account changetimestamps, versionnumber, etc.

Technical support and accountsecurity

Upon account closure2, 3

Single-sign-on providerand hashed ID

Account access using optional3rd party credential

Upon request or accountclosure2, 3

IP address Determine time zone uponsign-up

Not stored

Hashed IP address Account security After 1 year or uponaccount closure2, 3

Teacher

Hashed IP address Expedite classroom setup onmultiple devices

After 24 hours

Class name, class enddate, student names

Create progress reports andfacilitate program usage

Upon request, accountclosure3, or one yearafter class end date.

All Users

Hashed IP address,change logs

Network security After 90 days

De-identified andaggregated usage data

Product improvement anddevelopment, promotionalactivities, and educationalresearch

Until no longer useful

1. Student accounts: account closure occurs upon request, automatically after two years ofaccount inactivity, or one month after being unlinked from all parent and teacheraccounts.2. Parent accounts: account closure occurs upon request, or automatically after two yearsof account inactivity.3. Teacher accounts: account closure occurs upon request.

9 of 9
